

Eslam Amin

Home address: Cairo, Egypt

Email address: Eslamabdelnaser9@gmail.com

Mobile: +2 01000854201- +2 01010075146

Summary

Driven Service Delivery engineer with experience in virtualization technology which is very important to excel in the virtualization, Cloud Computing world, data center networking, hyper converged solution and mid-range storage for four years, Accomplished project engineer with a track record of successful. Seeking a position that will help expand my leadership opportunities while presenting me with new experience and knowledge in the field of data centers infrastructure and Cloud Architecture in Egypt and MENA region through a challenging position in a well-established organization.

Experience

January 2019 – Present

VAS Integrated Solutions



Job Role: Service Delivery Engineer.

HCI Specialist- vSAN- VCP- DCV- Red Hat | Dell EMC VxRail-Unity-Isilon | Dell Networking

- Provides implementation support of DELL EMC products at customer sites involving unique environments and configurations; this may include pre-site inspection, initial installation, troubleshooting, implementation, customization, integration, and product orientation for the customer.
- Installs Dell EMC products in a Mainframe and/or Open Systems hardware environment.
 Performs moderately complex and/or extended-stay software implementations. Demonstrate system capabilities, review software operation and management tools, and provide information to customer concerning the operation and use of DELL EMC products including "VxRail Unity –Isilon SAN Switches Dell Networking "

- Provides proactive recommendations to the customer for improving their use of DELL EMC storage solutions to help maximize their satisfaction with DELL EMC. Actively contributes to the configuration, layout and performance tuning of DELL EMC products including "VxRail Unity –Isilon SAN Switches Dell Networking"
- Performs necessary storage infrastructure maintenance as required. Health checks, hardware replacements, relocations and firmware/hardware upgrades.
- Apply technical knowledge base and use troubleshooting skills to Analyze and resolve called out problems in customer environments.
- Adheres to proper escalation and change control procedures, Prepares, maintains and submits activity/progress reports and time recording/management reports in accordance with published procedures.
- Stays current on technical specifications for hardware/software requirements of EMC and industry products and solutions through professional associations, trade journals, networking, and associated training and seminars.



Data Center Service Operation Engineer Nov 2017 – Dec 2018

- ☐ **Job Role:** System Center Operations Manager (SCOM) Engineer
 - Responsible for all System Center Operations Manager (SCOM) applications and Infrastructure.
 - Designed and Implemented SCOM 2012 environment with multiple management groups monitoring over 10,000 servers and devices.
 - Provides implementation Unified dashboard solution using Squaredup for System Center Operations Manager.
 - Provides implementation and configured standard Microsoft Management Packs: Active Directory, SharePoint, Lync, Exchange, SCCM, IIS, SQL, Forefront and Windows Server.
 - Provides implementation and configured 3rd party Management Packs: Vantage, Verba, Citrix\Comtrade, HP SIM, Enterprise Vault, and Symantec Anti virus.
 - Follow ITIL framework & practices Incident, Problem and Change Management via Remedy and Service-Now IT Service Management Suite.

Arabian International Company



OCT 2016 - Nov 2017

- Provide Troubleshooting and resolving incidents for 300+ employees in Egypt and Jeddah office remotely applications based on SLA and priority of incident.
- Ability to troubleshoot common hardware/software issues/ network connectivity problems manage, troubleshoot and create user's / mails account AD / Exchange Server
- Implementing, managing TMG firewall.
- Hyper-V operations.
- Manage standalone SQL Servers.
- Licensing Compliance reporting.
- Manage Supplier activities and delivery
- Responsible for Monitoring, installing AIC Egypt Servers.
- Managing application license utilization.
- Preparing solutions for automatic backups, events logging and alerting.
- Install and maintain computers, IP Phones, and other IT peripherals.
- Responsible for the installation, operation, and maintenance of computer systems and other technologies, such as Life-size video conference.
- Provide support to presentations and events that require IT support and conducted or promises – if required.
- Designing printing system to ensure the businesses continuity and minimize the cost of printing consumables.
- Analysis the most common incident constantly, work on it to get a permanent solution for the common incident due to that, will help us to enhance the service level.
- Manage Microsoft Skype for business
- Periodical reporting to IT Supervisor "Egypt"for new procedures, and new project to enhance the IT services in order to provide the service in high standard service level.
- Studying business requirement for new applications deployment and operations automation.
- Provide the new comers with induction to get the user's a warns about ticketing system and small training.
- Deliver troubleshooting reports and periodic preventive maintenance reports to my line manager.
- Implement creative software to Manage Inventory system.

Job Role: IT Assistant





- Provide help desk support for BC staff and Teaching Center classes (hardware, software, and peripherals)
- Manage system users (access rights and permissions).
- Install new / rebuild existing servers and configure hardware, peripherals, services, settings, directories, storage, etc.
- Basics configuration Cisco Switches/Routers/Firewalls.
- Ability to troubleshoot common hardware/software issues/ network connectivity problems.
- Provide support to presentations and events that require IT support and conducted or promises – if required
- Install and maintain computers, IPhones, and other IT peripherals.
- Rebuild computers with the approved images of windows and applications over SCCM Server.
- Manage the issuance of ID access cards.
- Manage incidents and services requests through ticketing service desk providing support to meet the needs of the business.
- Designs and produces basic reports.
- Responsible for the installation, operation, and maintenance of computer systems and other technologies, such as communication systems.
- Prioritize and schedule problems. Escalate problems (when required) to the appropriately experienced (onsite/customer) technician.
- Deliver trouble shooting reports and periodic preventive maintenance reports.
- Maintain wiring of user's desks and organizing cables of network cabinets.

Licenses & Certifications

- Certified in DES-6321 Specialist Implementation Engineer, VxRail Appliance Exam
- Certified in Specialist Implementation Engineer, Dell EMC Unity Solutions Version 2.0
- Certified in VMware Specialist vSAN 2020
- Certified in VMware Certified Professional 6.7 Data Center Virtualization 2019
- VMware vRealize Operations: Install, Configure, Manage [V7] Official Training
- Red Hat System Administration 1 &2 Online Training
- Certified in Specialist Platform Engineer, Isilon Version 3.0
- Certified in VxRail Appliance 4.x Deployment and Implementation
- Certified in Associate Information Storage and Management Version 3.0
- Certified in MCSE (Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer).
- Certified in CCNA (Cisco Certified Network Associate).

- Certified in Server Virtualization with Windows Server Hyper-V and System Center.
- Virtual Machine Manager "VMM" Online Training
- System Center Configuration Manager "SCCM " Online Training
- System Center Data Production Manager "DPM" Online Training
- System Center Operation Manager "SCOM" Online Training
- System Center Data Production Manager "SCDPM" Online Training
- ITIL Foundation V3 Online Training
- ITIL Intermediate Operation Online Training

Education

2011 - 2015

Modern Academy

- Bachelor of Computer Science

Behaviors and Skills

- Excellent Communication skills.
- Team Working and leadership.
- Being Accountable.
- Making it happen.
- Using technology Identifies Improvements.
- Analyzing Data and problems.
- Fast Learning, Team Player and Excellent Self-Study.
- Photoshop usage.
- Presentation skills.
- Work under Pressure.
- Active, Social, Hardworking, serious

Personal Information

Date of Birth: 18/08/1993Military status: Final exempt